Finding Aid for the Allyn Joslyn Papers PASC.0293
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Television Projects, (1950s-mid 1960s); Boxes 11-15, 18
  - Eve Arden Show (The)
    - New Tenant (The) - first draft script, 1957 Nov 11 (Box 12, Folder 11)
    - Rivals (The) - first draft script, 1957 Dec 11 (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - Ford Theatre
    - All For A Man - 4 photographs, ca. 1956 (Box 1, Folder 20)
      Thought to be publicity stills for the Ford Theatre television production, All For A Man with Linda Darnell.
    - Slide, Darling, Slide - final draft script, 1954 Jun 22 (Box 12, Folder 13)
      With script for promotional spot.
  - Gale Storm Show (The)
    - Happy Horoscope - third series script and call sheet, 1959 Mar 18 (Box 12, Folder 14)
      Script subtitled Oh! Susanna.
  - Great Adventure (The)
    - Man Who Stole New York City (The) - revised script, 1963 (Box 12, Folder 15)
  - Guestward Ho!
    - Dimples Goes Hollywood - script, 1960 Nov 2 (Box 12, Folder 16)
  - Harrigan and Son
    - You Can Fight City Hall - final revised script, 1960 Sep 20 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Lawman
    - Sin Buster (The) - first draft script, 1960 Nov 18 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - McKeever and the Colonel
    - All Quiet on the Westfield Front - script, 1962 Nov 27 (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - Army Mule (The) - script, 1962 Jul 18 (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - Blackwell the Retread - revised script, 1962 Jan 23 (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - Blackwell's Stand - script, 1962 Aug 22 (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - Bugle Sounds (The) - final shooting script and call sheet, 1962 Jun 7 (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - By the Book - final shooting script, call sheet and shooting schedule, 1962 Jun 6 (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - Cooky Crumbles (The) -script, 1962 Aug 17 (Box 13, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence and other papers, no date, 1962-63 (Box 13, Folder 3)
      Handwritten notes, itinerary, letters and telegrams all related to the McKeever show.
    - Feat of Clay - revised script, 1962 Nov 15 (Box 13, Folder 11)
    - For Dear Old Westfield - script, 1962 Oct 1 (Box 13, Folder 12)
    - General McKeever - script, 1962 Jul 12 (Box 13, Folder 13)
    - Hand in Glove -script, 1962 Sep 25 (Box 13, Folder 14)
    - Happy Birthday Colonel - revised script, 1962 Oct 29 (Box 13, Folder 15)
    - Love Comes to Westfield - script, 1962 Nov 26 (Box 13, Folder 16)
    - Make Room for Mother - script, 1962 Nov 15 (Box 13, Folder 17)
    - Mascot (The) - script, 1962 Jul 18 (Box 13, Folder 18)
    - McKeever and the Celestial Bells - revised script, 1962 Jun 15 (Box 13, Folder 19)
    - McKeever and the Colonel - 27 photographs, no date (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - McKeever and the Colonel - prop newspaper, no date (Box 19, Folder 1)
      2 copies.
    - McKeever Meets Munroe - script, call sheets and shooting schedule, 1963 Jan 30 (Box 13, Folder 20)
    - McKeever's Astronaut - revised script, 1962 Oct 17 (Box 13, Folder 21)
    - Neighbor (The) - script, 1962 Oct 30 (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Old Grad (The) - script, 1962 Dec 14 (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Old Grad (The) - script, 1963 Jan 16 (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Pilot - revised script, 1960 Nov 11 (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Pilot - script, no date (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - Project: Walkie-Talkie - script, 1962 Oct 31 (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - Relative Matter (A) - revised script, 1963 Jan 8 (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - Straight and Narrow - script, 1962 Jul 10 (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - Too Many Sergeants - script, 1962 Oct 3 (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - TV or Not TV - revised script, 1962 Jun 18 (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - Michael Shayne
    - Final Settlement - script, 1960 Dec 9 (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - My Three Sons
    - One Of Our Moose is Missing - revised script, 1964 Mar-Apr (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - NBC Matinee Theatre
    - Pushover (The) - title page, no date (Box 14, Folder 13)
  - Peter Loves Mary
    - Make a Million - script, 1960 Aug 3 (Box 14, Folder 14)
    - Make a Million - script, 1960 Aug 3 (Box 14, Folder 15)
  - Rawhide
    - Incident at Ashton Corners - final draft script, 1964 Feb 4 (Box 14, Folder 16)
  - Ray Bolger Show (The)
    - Ray Bolger Show (The) - script, no date (Box 14, Folder 17)
    - Where's Raymond? (The Shoe Store) - first draft script, 1954 Feb 26 (Box 14, Folder 18)
  - Target: The Corruptors
    - Book of Faces (A) - revised script, 1963 Mar 7 (Box 14, Folder 19)
  - Those Whiting Girls
    - Barbara's Love Song - script, no date (Box 14, Folder 20)
  - Tom Ewell Show (The)
    - Prying Eye (The) - script and call sheet, 1961 Feb 9 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Topper
    - Topper - script, no date (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Unknown Television Projects
    - Cracker Barrel - An Original Weekly, One-Hour Live Television Program - project proposal, 1959 Feb 10 (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - Lucky Louis Series - The Boy Who Talked to Himself - script, no date (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - Publicity Girl - teleplay by Jerry Davis, no date (Box 11, Folder 10)
    - Real George - first draft script, 1953 Mar 29 (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Untouchables (The)
    - Silent Partner - first draft teleplay and call sheet, 1961 Oct 27 (Box 15, Folder 4)
      Memo and copies of unsigned contracts from [Sid Gold] (not necessarily related to The Untouchables).
  - Walt Disney's Wonderful World of Color
    - Kilroy Part I - shooting script, 1964 Jul 15 (Box 15, Folder 5)
      The War at Wilton Junction.
    - Kilroy Part II - shooting script and call sheets, 1964 Jul 15 (Box 15, Folder 6)
      Oscar the Great.
    - Kilroy Part III - first draft teleplay, 1964 Jun 5 (Box 15, Folder 7)
      The Reluctant Dog-Catcher.
  - Westinghouse Preview Theatre
    - Heave Ho Harrigan (created as a comedy series for television) - script, 1959 Mar 19 (Box 15, Folder 8)
- Correspondence, (ca. 1940s-1960s); Box 2
  The Correspondence series is a mix of letters, telegrams, and/or cards to Joslyn that appear to be related to both personal matters and professional activities. Also included are a very small number of items to Josylyn's wife and daughter. The files are arranged alphabetically by file titles which reflect the contents of the folders. All file titles have been supplied by the processor.
  - unspecified
    - Business correspondence to Allyn Joslyn, 1940s (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Business correspondence to Allyn Joslyn, 1950s (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Business correspondence to Allyn Joslyn, 1960s (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Fan mail to Allyn Joslyn, 1931, 1944, no date (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - To Allyn Joslyn from friends, no date (Box 2, Folder 7)
      Including Charles Coburn and Glenn Ford among others.
    - To Allyn Joslyn from Mother, 1942, 1957 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - To Dorothy Joslyn, 1933, 1944-45 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - To Linda Joslyn, no date (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - To Mr. and Mrs. Joslyn, 1942, 1962-63 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Memorabilia, (1930a-1960s); Boxes 2, 19
  The Memorabilia series includes a small collection of playbills, programs, memorabilia, and other printed ephemera collected by Joslyn. Also included is a small amount of membership mailings/printed ephemera from professional organizations. The files are arranged alphabetically by folder title which reflect the contents of the folder. All file titles have been supplied by the processor.
  - unspecified
    - Actors' Equity - membership ephemera, 1936, 1963, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Allyn Joslyn drawing (unsigned by artist), no date (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Allyn Joslyn personal memorabilia, no date (Box 2, Folder 1)
      With address book, miscellaneous handwritten notes, SAG identification card, MGM questionnaire pertaining to the Draft, menu card from the S.S. Saramacca. Also includes Actors Equity card for AJ's wife Dorothy Yockel.
    - Assorted event playbills and programs, 1935-36, 1951, 1958, no date (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Celebrity Service Information and Research Daily Bulletin, 1945 June (Box 2, Folder 26)
      Celebrity of today: Allyn Joslyn.
    - Coffee House (The) - membership ephemera, 1959 Apr 15 (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - Masquers Club - membership certificate, no date (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - Players - membership ephemera, 1930s-1970s (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - Screen Actors Guild - membership ephemera, 1942, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - Sheet Music, 1921, no date (Box 2, Folder 20)
      Forgive Me, Tears Made You Mine; and Greenwhich Village Follies: Swanee River Moon, and When Dreams Come True.
    - Talent Scout, 1945 Nov (Box 2, Folder 27)
      Lists editor Alan Allyn (could this be AJ?).
- Press Clippings, (ca. 1940s-1964 and 1976); Boxes 15-19
  The Press Clippings series is a mixture of reviews, publicity, and promotional write-ups about Joslyn and/or the various projects or events in which he was involved during his career. The series is arranged chronologically into sub-series by decade. The chronological arrangement of the series often brings together information about particular projects, during specific periods of Joslyn's career such as Arsenic and Old Lace (stage version), Immortal Sergeant, Titanic, and The Wife Takes a Flyer. Whenever possible, known project titles are listed in the notes field. A portion of the clippings were sent to Joslyn by the Henry Arnsten Public Relations company. The files within each sub-series are arranged chronologically. Joslyn's name appears in the notes field in the abbreviated form, "AJ."
  - 1930s
    - Clipping on scrapbook page, ca. 1931 (Box 15, Folder 19)
      Only one page of clippings found in scrapbook.
    - Clippings - 1930s (Box 16, Folder 2)
      With information for Boy Meets Girl, Fast and Furious, and They Won't Forget, among others.
  - 1940s
    - Box Office Digest publications, 1945-46; 1950 (Box 18, Folder 19)
      Three issues of the publication mentioning Joslyn and/or projects for which he was involved).
    - Clippings - 1940-41 (Box 16, Folder 3)
      With information for Arsenic and Old Lace, among others.
    - Clippings - 1944 (Box 16, Folder 12)
      With information for Strange Affair and The Imposter, among others.
    - Clippings - 1945-49 (Box 16, Folder 13)
      Publicity with brief mentions and/or reference to AJ.
    - Clippings - Apr-Aug 1943, 1943 Apr-Aug (Box 16, Folder 10)
      With information for Heaven Can Wait and HellZaPoppin, USO Camp show, among others.
    - Clippings - Dec 1942, 1942 Dec (Box 16, Folder 8)
      Publicity with brief mentions and or reference to AJ.
    - Clippings - Jan-Feb 1942, 1942 Jan-Feb (Box 16, Folder 4)
      With information for I Wake Up Screaming, among others.
    - Clippings - Jan-Mar 1943, 1943 Jan-Mar (Box 16, Folder 9)
      With information for Immortal Sergeant, among others.
    - Clippings - Jun 1942, 1942 Jun (Box 16, Folder 7)
      With information for The Wife Takes a Flyer.
    - Clippings - Mar-May 1942 (1 of 2), 1942 Mar-May (Box 16, Folder 5)
      With information for Bedtime Story, among others.
    - Clippings - Mar-May 1942 (2 of 2), 1942 Mar-May (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - Clippings - Sep-Dec 1943, 1943 Sep-Dec (Box 16, Folder 11)
      With information for Dangerous Blondes.
    - Motion Picture Herald publications, 1943-45 (Box 19, Folder 6)
      Six issues of the publication mentioning Joslyn and/or projects for which he was involved.
  - 1950s
    - Clippings - 1950-51 (Box 16, Folder 14)
      With information for Harriet Craig and As Young As You Feel.
    - Clippings - 1952 (Box 16, Folder 15)
      With information for Collector's Item, among others.
    - Clippings - 1953 (1 of 2) (Box 16, Folder 16)
      With information for Island in the Sky, among others.
    - Clippings - 1953 (2 of 2) (Box 16, Folder 17)
      With information for Titanic, among others.
    - Clippings - Apr 1956 (1 of 2), 1956 Apr (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - Clippings - Apr 1956 (2 of 2), 1956 Apr (Box 17, Folder 2)
    - Clippings - Aug 1956 (1 of 2), 1956 Aug (Box 17, Folder 8)
    - Clippings - Aug 1956 (2 of 2), 1956 Aug (Box 17, Folder 9)
    - Clippings - Aug-Oct 1958, 1958 Aug-Oct (Box 18, Folder 4)
    - Clippings - Dec 1955 (1 of 3), 1955 Dec (Box 16, Folder 18)
    - Clippings - Dec 1955 (2 of 3), 1955 Dec (Box 16, Folder 19)
    - Clippings - Dec 1955 (3 of 3), 1955 Dec (Box 16, Folder 20)
    - Clippings - Dec 1956, 1956 Dec (Box 17, Folder 17)
    - Clippings - Dec 1957, 1957 Dec (Box 17, Folder 25)
    - Clippings - Feb 1956 (1 of 3), 1956 Feb (Box 16, Folder 23)
    - Clippings - Feb 1956 (2 of 3), 1956 Feb (Box 16, Folder 24)
    - Clippings - Feb 1956 (3 of 3), 1956 Feb (Box 16, Folder 25)
    - Clippings - Feb-Mar 1958, 1958 Feb-Mar (Box 18, Folder 3)
    - Clippings - Jan 1956 (1 of 2), 1956 Jan (Box 16, Folder 21)
    - Clippings - Jan 1956 (2 of 2), 1956 Jan (Box 16, Folder 22)
    - Clippings - Jan 1958 (1 of 2), 1958 Jan (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - Clippings - Jan 1958 (2 of 2), 1958 Jan (Box 18, Folder 2)
    - Clippings - Jan-Feb 1957, 1957 Jan-Feb (Box 17, Folder 18)
    - Clippings - Jul 1956 (1 of 2), 1956 Jul (Box 17, Folder 6)
    - Clippings - Jul 1956 (2 of 2), 1956 Jul (Box 17, Folder 7)
    - Clippings - Jun 1956, 1956 Jun (Box 17, Folder 5)
    - Clippings - Jun-Aug 1957, 1957 Jun-Aug (Box 17, Folder 19)
    - Clippings - Mar 1956 (1 of 3), 1956 Mar (Box 16, Folder 26)
    - Clippings - Mar 1956 (2 of 3), 1956 Mar (Box 16, Folder 27)
    - Clippings - Mar 1956 (3 of 3), 1956 Mar (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - Clippings - May 1956 (1 of 2), 1956 May (Box 17, Folder 3)
    - Clippings - May 1956 (2 of 2), 1956 May (Box 17, Folder 4)
    - Clippings - Nov 1956 (1 of 3), 1956 Nov (Box 17, Folder 14)
    - Clippings - Nov 1956 (2 of 3), 1956 Nov (Box 17, Folder 15)
    - Clippings - Nov 1956 (3 of 3), 1956 Nov (Box 17, Folder 16)
    - Clippings - Nov 1957 (1 of 2), 1957 Nov (Box 17, Folder 23)
    - Clippings - Nov 1957 (2 of 2), 1957 Nov (Box 17, Folder 24)
    - Clippings - Oct 1956 (1 of 2), 1956 Oct (Box 17, Folder 12)
    - Clippings - Oct 1956 (2 of 2), 1956 Oct (Box 17, Folder 13)
    - Clippings - Oct 1957 (1 of 2), 1957 Oct (Box 17, Folder 21)
    - Clippings - Oct 1957 (2 of 2), 1957 Oct (Box 17, Folder 22)
    - Clippings - Sep 1956 (1 of 2), 1956 Sep (Box 17, Folder 10)
    - Clippings - Sep 1956 (2 of 2), 1956 Sep (Box 17, Folder 11)
    - Clippings - Sep 1957, 1957 Sep (Box 17, Folder 20)
  - 1960s
    - Clippings - 1961-63 (1 of 2) (Box 18, Folder 5)
      With information for McKeever and the Colonel, among others.
    - Clippings - 1961-63 (2 of 2) (Box 18, Folder 6)
      Hollywood Reporter and Variety publications.
    - Clippings - 1964 (1 of 2) (Box 18, Folder 7)
      With information for The Addams Family.
    - Clippings - 1964 (2 of 2) (Box 18, Folder 8)
      With information for The Addams Family and Kilroy.
  - 1970s
    - Clippings - 1976 (Box 18, Folder 9)
      Hollywood Reporter mention of AJ's heart operations.
- Publications, (ca. mid-1940s, mid-1950s, and 1962); Boxes 15, 18-20
  The Publication series consists of industry publications that appear to have been collected by Joslyn and do not appear to be directly related to his personal or professional life. The bulk of the series are issues of the Motion Picture Daily (1945), of which Joslyn was a subscriber. Other titles include the Hollywood Reporter, Variety, and single issues of miscellaneous magazines. The series is arranged alphabetically by publication titles.
  - unspecified
    - Cue - publication, 1952 Feb 23 (Box 15, Folder 15)
    - Hollywood Reporter and Daily Variety, 1962 (Box 18, Folder 20)
    - Motion Picture Daily (1 of 2), 1945 (Box 20, Folder 1)
      Miscellaneous issues spanning Mar, Apr, Aug, Sep, Oct 1945.
    - Motion Picture Daily (2 of 2), 1945 (Box 20, Folder 2)
      Incomplete issues for Nov and Dec 1945.
    - New York Times - World's Fair Section, 1939 Mar 5 (Box 19, Folder 2)
    - Spotlite: official publication of Hollywood Athletic Club - publication, 1946 Dec (Box 15, Folder 16)
    - TV-Radio Life, 1956 Jan (Box 15, Folder 17)
      Volume 32, Issue 32.
- Publicity Stills and Photographs, (no dates); Boxes 1, 19
  The Publicity Stills and Photographs series includes a small number of stills and photographs that were not identified with any specific motion picture, television, stage, or radio related project. Included are a small number of head shots of Joslyn, four USO-related photographs, and a very small number of personal photographs with family members. The files are arranged alphabetically by file titles reflecting the contents of each folder.
  - unspecified
    - Duplicate photographs from collection - 47 items, no date (Box 1, Folder 28)
      Duplicates of photographs in the collection consisting mostly of McKeever and the Colonel and AJ head shots.
    - Allyn Joslyn and others photographs - 11 oversize items, no date (Box 19, Folder 5)
      Headshots of Joslyn (3), scene shots from unknown stage production (4 including one duplicate), and unknown female(s) (4 including two duplicates).
    - Allyn Joslyn head shots and publicity stills - 37 items, no date (Box 1, Folder 23)
      Includes a photograph of a sketch of young AJ.
    - Allyn Joslyn publicity photographs - 30 photographs, no date (Box 1, Folder 24)
      Publicity shots alone and with others, mostly unidentified (30 items).
    - Gish, Dorothy - 1 photograph inscribed by Gish, no date (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - HellZaPoppin, USO Camp shows - 4 photographs, ca. 1943 (Box 1, Folder 22)
      Group shots including Lynn Bari and Milton Douglas among others.
    - Reiner, Carl - 6 photographs, no date (Box 1, Folder 27)
      Publicity photographs (6) and biography of Reiner (2 copies).
    - Unidentified negatives - 4 items, no date (Box 1, Folder 25)
      Too small or cloudy to clearly identify people in negatives.